<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carlos Valenzuela</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Carlos Valenzuela</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bexar County Changes in Household and Housing, 2007-2016</title>
      <link>/post/bexar-county-changes-in-household-and-housing-2007-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/post/bexar-county-changes-in-household-and-housing-2007-2016/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I looked at changes in household income and housing values between 2007 and 2016. The reason for looking at these changes was due to a recent post provided by the US Census Bureau that stated San Antonio added the most residents between 2016 and 2017.
San Antonio, as much of Texas, experienced increased net in-migration since the Great Recession (2008). As a result, I wondered how these changes in population could have affected housing values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bexar County Household Income and Housing Values, 2007-2016</title>
      <link>/post/bexar-county-household-income-and-housing-values-2007-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/post/bexar-county-household-income-and-housing-values-2007-2016/</guid>
      <description>My hometown of San Antonio added the most residents than any other city in the country between 2016 and 2017 (link). Since 2007, the population in San Antonio and surrounding areas have grown rapidly. One of the questions I have is, how have recent changes impacted housing values in the area during this time? How has household income fared in comparison? These questions are important because rapid changes in population can put a strain on the housing supply, which can lead to drastic increasing housing values due to a limited housing supply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I am a demographer who loves working with data and emerging data science tools.
I decided to start this blog for a couple of reasons. The first is for me to document social science topics, statistical techniques, and data science tools I am interested in. The second reason is to help people like me learn about the potential and utility of data and techniques available without having to start from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I earned my PhD in Applied Demography from the University of Texas at San Antonio (2013). I also hold an MS and BA in Sociology from the University of Texas at San Antonio (2010) and University of Texas at Austin (2004) respectively.
During my graduate studies, I worked on projects related to various social issues, including: homelessness and inequality, residential energy consumption, and demography (fertility and migration). During this time, I acquired a great passion for analytics, especially using programming and mapping.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>