<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Carlos Valenzuela</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Carlos Valenzuela</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Subset of Shapefile Geography in QGIS</title>
      <link>/post/take-subset-of-shapefile-geography-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/post/take-subset-of-shapefile-geography-qgis/</guid>
      <description>In the last post, we opened a shapefile that contained all census block groups in Texas in QGIS. In this post, I provide steps for taking a subset of a shapefile, particularly by keeping block groups located in Bexar County.
First, open the Texas shapefile and hover over the zoom in icon, which is a magnifying glass with a plus sign inside

Then, zoom in on the region of Texas where Bexar County is located</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Shapefile in QGIS</title>
      <link>/post/open-shapefile-in-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/post/open-shapefile-in-qgis/</guid>
      <description>QGIS is great option for producing maps. One can create maps by downloading shapefiles and opening them in QGIS.
In this exercise, I downloaded a shapefile of all blockgroups in Texas from the U.S. Census Bureau (link). The file is a geodatabase and contains some sociodemographic data.

Drag the geodatabase to QGIS and a dialogue box will open
Then, click Select All
Click OK
Done!
In the next post, I will show h.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install QGIS with Anaconda</title>
      <link>/post/install-qgis-with-anaconda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/post/install-qgis-with-anaconda/</guid>
      <description>In grad school, I enjoyed working on spatial analyses using R and ArcMap. Since I am no longer and grad school, and have no appetite in spending hundreds of dollars to use software, I would like to get more comfortable using QGIS, which is free, open source, and available on Windows, Mac, and Linux.
Recently, I installed Bodhi Linux on my old laptop. It&amp;rsquo;s a lightweight Linux distro, which is useful since my laptop is already 8 years old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes in Tenure among Single Family Housing Units in Bexar County, 2007-2016</title>
      <link>/post/changes-in-tenure-among-single-family-housing-units-in-bexar-county-2007-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/post/changes-in-tenure-among-single-family-housing-units-in-bexar-county-2007-2016/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I found that renter occupied housing units in Bexar County (as well as the rest of Texas), increased 15% between 2007 and 2016. I mentioned it was possible that growth in housing units may have kept pace with that of households due to growth in apartment complexes. However, I wasn’t really sure if this was the case.
During the Great Recession, many households lost their homes due to default, be it from job loss or rising interests rates for those with adjustable rate mortgages (ARM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thanks and Other Thoughts</title>
      <link>/post/some-thanks-and-other-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/post/some-thanks-and-other-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I want to thank people in the R community for everything they do to, such as creating new packages and platforms for people to share their ideas to the world. I am really grateful to people like Yihui who created blogdown and bookdown. I can&amp;rsquo;t say enough of how blogdown has changed the way I document and communicate analyses with others&amp;hellip;and with such ease!
I started using blogdown a couple of weeks ago and I can&amp;rsquo;t believe how easy it has been using blogdown to install hugo, write a post, and publish all in one place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bexar County Changes in Household and Housing, 2007-2016</title>
      <link>/post/bexar-county-changes-in-household-and-housing-2007-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/post/bexar-county-changes-in-household-and-housing-2007-2016/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I looked at changes in household income and housing values between 2007 and 2016. The reason for looking at these changes was due to a recent post provided by the US Census Bureau that stated San Antonio added the most residents between 2016 and 2017.
San Antonio, as much of Texas, experienced increased net in-migration since the Great Recession (2008). As a result, I wondered how these changes in population could have affected housing values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bexar County Household Income and Housing Values, 2007-2016</title>
      <link>/post/bexar-county-household-income-and-housing-values-2007-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/post/bexar-county-household-income-and-housing-values-2007-2016/</guid>
      <description>My hometown of San Antonio added the most residents than any other city in the country between 2016 and 2017 (link). Since 2007, the population in San Antonio and surrounding areas have grown rapidly. One of the questions I have is, how have recent changes impacted housing values in the area during this time? How has household income fared in comparison? These questions are important because rapid changes in population can put a strain on the housing supply, which can lead to drastic increasing housing values due to a limited housing supply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>jour4life@gmail.com (Carlos Valenzuela)</author>
      <guid>/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I am a demographer who loves working with data and emerging data science tools.
I decided to start this blog for a couple of reasons. The first is for me to document social science topics, statistical techniques, and data science tools I am interested in. The second reason is to help people like me learn about the potential and utility of data and techniques available without having to start from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>